UNITE HERE New York Joint Board Memorabilia Banners 6200 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE New York Joint Board Memorabilia Banners
1913-1937
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE
UNITE HERE New York Joint Board
6200 MB
47.25 cubic feet
47.2 linear ft.
Banners.
8255154
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 24, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 27, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees International Union; UNITE HERE (Organization)
8255154
- Pants Makers Union; [union seal]; Greater New York; Organized 1887 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Wool felt, gold appliqu on red background. Gold braid on edges, fringe on V bottom. Hanging loops at top
- Knee Pants Makers Union; Local [union label] No. 19; ACW of A; Affil with AF of L; Org. 1888; New York, 1933-1937 (Box 3)
  Gold stitching on red background, decorative designs. Union label with sewing machine and scissors in hand. Fringe on over skirt and scalloped bottom. Tassels at bottom. [probably 1933-1937]
- Leisurewear-Robe and Sportswear Workers Union; [eagle with broken chains and union seal with "In Union Victory and Freedom"]; Local 284, ACW of A (Box 4)
  Gold stitching on red background with large eagle, union seal on shield over orange-filled "V." gold braid at edges, fringe on bottom. Hangs from loops at top.
- Lithuanian Local 54 Coat Makers; [union seal]; Organized Nov. 13, 1901, Brooklyn, NY (Box 5)
  Two sided banner in English and Lithuanian. Gold stitching on red backing. White center of union seal. Fringe at bottom and on over skirt. Decorative designs. Tassels at bottom. 68 x 46.5 plus tassels and loops
- Wholesale Clothing clerks Union; Local 158, ACW of A [union seal], Chartered 1933 (Box 6)
  Gold and red edged stitching on blue background. Gold fringe on over-skirt and scalloped bottom. Tassels at bottom. Hangs from loops at top. BACK. Makers label Kraus and Sons, Inc. Union Made, 11 E. 22nd St., NY and Sanitary Union Label A66
- Italian Local 176, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America [union seal], Brooklyn, NY (Box 7)
  Gold stitching on pale maroon background with laurel leaves under seal and other decorative designs. Fringe at scalloped bottom. Hangs from sleeve at top.
- New York Clothing Cutters Union, [ACWA union label], Local Big 4, ACW of A (Box 1)
  Cream stitching on red background. Additional decorative designs. Fringe at top over skirt and scalloped bottom with tassels. Hangs from loops at top
- Italian Local 142, Amalgamated Clothing Workers [ACWA union seal], Coat Tailors, B'klyn, NY (Box 8)
  Cream stitching on red background with laurel leaves under seal. Gold braid around edges, tassels on side ropes. Fringe at scalloped bottom, hung from sleeve at top
- Canvas and Pad Makers U (over older text?) of United Brotherhood of Tailors, Local 153 (over older#), Our [union label] Label UGW of A, Affil. With AF of L, Org. July 28, 1910 [over other date] New York (Box 9)
  Cream stitching on red background, fringed overskirt and bottom edge, decorative designs. Tassels at bottom. Hung from loops at top
- Pants Pressers Union, Local 40 [clasped hands], ACW of A [flat iron], Org. May 1907 (Box 10)
  Cream stitching on red background. Dark gold braid around edges. Fringe at over skirt and bottom (mostly missing). Hangs by sleeve.
- Greater New York Coat Makers [union seal], Local No. 25, Re-Organized April 25, 1932 (Box 11)
  Meant to be framed. No edging. Outline with gold braid on red background in traditional banner shape with decorative designs. Very light weight.
- New York Joint Board, ACW of A [union label], Organized 1915, New York (Box 12)
  Cream stitching on red background, NY Jt Bd on orange background (covering old stitching?). STITCHED and Reworked OVER older United Garment Workers (UGW of A) organized 1892- banner
- Greater New York Coat Makers [union seal], Local NO. 25, Re-Organized April 25, 1932 (Box 13)
  Older true-banner version of #11. Gold stitching on red background, gold braid around edges, decorative stitching, fringe at over skirt and scalloped bottom. Hung by loops. BACK Sanitary Union Label, 993 or 998
- Sheepskin, Leather & Outerwear [ACTWU seal], Local 17, Org. 1932 (Box 14)
  Gold writing on red background. White seal in center. ?Nylon?. Gold fringe at bottom. Hangs from sleeve at top.
- Italian Coat Maker Union, Local 63 [clasped hands], ACW of A, Org. 23 April 1913 (Box 15)
  Meant to be framed. No edging. Gold braid outlines traditional banner shape on pink background. Image 0160 in frame.
- New York Journeymen Tailors [eagle with American shield] Protective and Benevolent Union Organized 1862 / [back] - Presented By the Ladies of the New York Journeymen Tailors Protective and Benevolent Union August 7[?], 1887 (Box 16)
  Cream stitching on blue-green background. Gold braid around edges. Fringe at bottom. Hung from sleeve at top (added later?) / [back]- Cream stitching on cream background with pale gold, red and brown oak and fern branches, nuts and berries Red felt hanging sleeve added later, some added fabric and stitching roughly added long ago to control losses and tears.